Isaac M. Jordan – Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom IsaacJordan95@gmail.com

http://isaacjordan.me http://uk.linkedin.com/in/ijordan http://github.com/isaac-jordan

Summary

Professional software engineer with 5 years experience in large and small enterprise environments building innovative products aiming to be market leaders. Experienced in a variety of languages and technology stacks, most recently with Java/Kotlin, JavaScript, TypeScript, and AWS services (Lambda, SQS, DynamoDB, S3).

Work Experience

AWS (Amazon CodeGuru Profiler)

London, UK

Software Development Engineer II [TypeScript, React, Kotlin, AWS]

Sep 2019 - Present

- Developed features in a new product area and global team, such as simplified profiling visualisations, onboarding workflows for new users, and new APIs to correlate data across AWS services. Wrote the first public blog post.
- Took on an informal engineering team lead role, mentoring other engineers through projects and regularly improved and simplified development and operational processes. E.g. introduced Kanban and simpler prioritisation discussions, follow-the-sun on-call rotas, safer launch processes, weekly dashboard reviews, and reusable infrastructure libraries (removing over 10k lines of code).
- Took ownership over the console (front-end) infrastructure and codebase, ensuring a high quality bar as new engineers took on front-end work and the service extended to 5 new AWS regions. Personally improved page performance by 50% and reduced bundle size by 20%.

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer I & II [Java, TypeScript, React, AWS]

Sep 2017 - Sep 2019

- Integrated my team's video rendering API with a public Amazon Advertising product. Utilised AWS Lambda/DynamoDB/S3 for a new micro-service mediator with automated alarming, along with new TypeScript/React components.
- Launched a new programmatic video advertising program and increased ad performance by 10x in 6 months through rigorous A/B experimentation, exceeding our team goal of \$500k sales.
- Improved my team's development and release processes over time, e.g. introduced SonarQube for month-on-month code quality improvements, and new tools to track the team's operational load.

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer Intern [Java, OpenCV]

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

- Created a patent-awarded prototype application to convert existing video content into personalisable videos in a fast (real-time) and automated fashion, using a Java/OpenCV pipeline.

TBR Global Chauffeuring

Glasgow, UK

Software Developer (Intern, followed by Part-Time) [C#, MVC.NET, JavaScript] Jun 2015 - May 2016

- Reduced data ingestion time by 95% for Emirates Airline jobs by preprocessing data using OpenAddressesUK and Google Maps APIs, saving hours of manual labour each week.

Chi Squared Innovations

Remote

Software Developer (Part-Time) [Python, Django, JavaScript, d3.js]

Sep 2014 - Jun 2015

Education

University of Glasgow

Glasgow, UK

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science (First Class)

2013 - 2017

- Received top-of-class prize in Year 3, and first prize at Glasgow University Hackathon 2015.